

Willy Fontenelle

Product Designer | UI/UX | Design System | Front-end React

Homepage: willyfontenelle.github.io
Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/willyfontenelle
Portfolio: medium.com/@willyfontenelle

+55 (21) 97155-9194 | willyfontenelle@gmail.com

Rio de Janeiro, RJ - Brasil

I've been working with product design for over 10 years in app, platform and website projects as a UI/UX designer and proposing solutions that not only achieve business goals, but also improve user life and make development more efficient.

My work has always been very close to the technology area, developing interfaces and systems, but never leaving aside a full understanding of the problem, which is why I was also able to get involved with research and discovery processes.

I'm currently studying front end web programming and ReactJS, in order to extend my contribution to the team and the project and ensure more autonomy in the technical documentation of a design system.

Languages: Portuguese (native), English (advanced) and Spanish (intermediate).

Experience

Hurb | 2022-2023 (Senior Design System Analyst)

One of the largest digital travel agencies in Latin America

- Creation of the company's first design system documentation, Suitcase;
- Conducting rituals with the members of our task force;
- Definition of the first version of design tokens (variables) and components;
- Presentation of workshops and support to product and design teams;
- Implementation of surveys with teams to evolve collaboration processes;

Ubook (Audimo) | 2021 - 2022 (Senior Product Designer)

Audio entertainment app with books, documentaries and podcasts

- Organization and documentation of the design library (styles, components and templates);
- Prototyping new features for the app and website;
- Responsible for the approval routines of new versions;

Onawa | 2019-2021 (Product Designer)

White-label B2B platform for relationship selling

- Conception and creation of the People Commerce platform, serving the Wine Events club;
- Creation and documentation of the design library (styles, components and templates);
- · Driving discovery and research methodologies;

Education and certificates

Bachelor of Product Design - PUC-Rio | 2007-2011

- React Js from zero to advanced in practice Matheus Fraga (Udemy) | 2023
- Workshop Design System Advanced Glauber Laender (Nubank) | 2023
- Design System Specialist Meiuca | 2023
- UX Team Summit (Design System) Mergo User Experience | 2022
- Design System in Code Meiuca | 2022
- Front-end Alura | 2021
- UX Foundations: Style Guides and Design Systems Linkedin | 2021